<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Github on Home</title>
    <link>https://vbgupta.github.io/Website/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Github on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vbgupta.github.io/Website/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exoplanet-Habitability-Prediction 🌎</title>
      <link>https://vbgupta.github.io/Website/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vbgupta.github.io/Website/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>ML model to predict habitability of an exoplanet Overview: https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/kepler/overview/index.html
The Kepler Mission is specifically designed to survey our region of the Milky Way galaxy to discover hundreds of Earth-size and smaller planets in or near the habitable zone and determine the fraction of the hundreds of billions of stars in our galaxy that might have such planets.
Kepler Science The scientific objective of the Kepler Mission is to explore the structure and diversity of planetary systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heart-Disease-Classification ♥</title>
      <link>https://vbgupta.github.io/Website/post/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vbgupta.github.io/Website/post/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning Classification Model to Predict Heart Disease  This notebook looks into using various Python-based libraries in an attempt to build a machine learning model capable of predicting whether of not someone has heart disease based on specific medical attributes.
 We are going to take the following approach  Problem definition Data Evaluation Features Modelling Experimentation  1. Problem Definition: Given clinical parameters about a patient, can we predict whether of not a patient has heart disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting-Bulldozer-Price-ML-Regression-Time-Series 🚜</title>
      <link>https://vbgupta.github.io/Website/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vbgupta.github.io/Website/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Predicting Bulldozer 🚜 Price Using Machine Learning - Regression
1. Problem Definition How well can we predict the future sale price of a bulldozer, given its characteristics and previously given examples and is the sale price similar?
2. Data The data is downloaded from Kaggle Blue Book for Bulldozers: https://www.kaggle.com/c/bluebook-for-bulldozers/
The data for this competition is split into three parts:
Train.csv is the training set, which contains data through the end of 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deloitte-Datathon</title>
      <link>https://vbgupta.github.io/Website/post/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vbgupta.github.io/Website/post/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Winner: Deloitte&amp;rsquo;s first ever 48 hour Datathon at Penn State Team Memebers during the competition:  Harsh Gupta: https://github.com/harshg28101999 Divya Rustagi: https://github.com/DivyaRustagi10 Daniel Gwak Kashish Patel  The Competition: Find the best market/city for the company to launch their ride share service.
This repo is my take on the competition
What I used: Google Colab Python 3.8 Python Packages: Pandas, Matplotlib Tableau
What I did: The plan was to look through the data and find relevant columns to find the best market to deploy the car share service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MultiClass-Lung-Image-Classification 😤</title>
      <link>https://vbgupta.github.io/Website/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vbgupta.github.io/Website/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a lung emoji so&amp;hellip;
Images of Lungs:
 Normal Lung    Bacterial Infected Lung    Virus Infected Lung    Deep Learning Training Results   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dog-Breed-Classification 🐶</title>
      <link>https://vbgupta.github.io/Website/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vbgupta.github.io/Website/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Built an end-to-end multi-class image classifier using Tensorflow and Tensorflow Hub.
120 Different Dog Breeds 🐕🐩🐕‍🦺
1. Problem
Identify the breed of a dog given an image of a dog.
2. Data
The data os from Kaggle&amp;rsquo;s dog breed identification competition. https://www.kaggle.com/c/dog-breed-identification/data
3. Evaluation
The evaluation is a file with prediction probabilities for each dog breed. https://www.kaggle.com/c/dog-breed-identification/overview/evaluation
4. Features
Some information about the data:
Unstructured data 120 dog breeds 10,000 + images in training and validation set</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
